

## Máximo García

Fullstack Developer

- Computer engineering bachelor in UPM, Spain. Feb 2021.
- ▶ Uppsala, Sweden
- Spanish citizen

## Skills

Web design & development

Software development 3+ yrs.

SSI & Blockchain 1+ yrs.

Data science 6+ mon.

# Languages/Tools

- TS, JS, Java, Python, Go, Node
- Git, Docker, Bash
- Springboot, Django, Flask
- MongoDB, Postgres
- Tensorflow, keras, matplotlib
- React, Vue, Angular, Svelte, lit, TailwindCSS
- Figma, Adobe XD
- Haskell, Erlang

## **Biography**

My name is Máximo J. García Martínez. I am a Fullstack developer at Nimiq, working in the cryptocurrency domain. I also worked in the SSI and AI fields. I graduated from UPM in 2021 with a BSc in Computer Engineering where I obtained a grade with honours in my thesis on neural networks. During my studies, I have worked on making websites and backends for different projects. I am always thirsty to learn new concepts. I love the open source world and working in a team where I can learn from others with more experience. Currently, I am living in Stuttgart where I am learning German.

# Work experience

### Frontend Developer

Nimia

Jan. 2022 - Today

As a front-end developer on a cutting-edge crypto project, I use my technical expertise and creative problem-solving skills. Using Vue 3, I create intuitive and engaging user experiences while contributing to the development of new features. In a fast-paced startup environment, I thrive on the challenge of finding innovative solutions to complex problems and delivering high quality results. I also regularly share my technical knowledge by writing technical blog posts and contributing to design projects.

#### Researcher SSI at LACChain

Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Collaborator

I had to discuss and recommend solutions on some of the aspects they had designed to avoid problems with the GDPR law and at the same time to obtain interoperability between the networks in the near future.

These problems are mainly based on the VC Data Model from W3C and different known attacks with which private data could be obtained directly from the blockchain network.

#### Researcher SSI at Alastria

Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Member of Alastria Core & Architecure Team

Responsible for the specification and development of the Alastria ID. We had to discuss problems and their solutions. Then we had to implement those changes in the open source libraries written in TS.

#### Junior Fullstack

Feb. 2021 - Dec. 2021

 $\label{eq:continuous} \mbox{ Department of Blokchain} \mid \mbox{ Cybersecurity unit } \mbox{ Inetum}$ 

I was responsible for building and leading a small team of junior frontend developers with different web projects in different areas: Showcases of Alastria technology, pages used by developers for testing and dashboards for entities to manage configurations. For those projects we used TS with Nuxt, React and Angular. My job consisted mainly of designing the UI and then monitoring, advising and checking the quality of the code through PRs. I also had to manage the frontend team to meet deadlines and organise developer tasks using AGILE methods. At the same time, I was also responsible for the deployment of those websites and web applications using Docker and nginx.

I had also few backend tasks such as develop different libraries in Java to: communicate with the blockchain network and to create, sign and verify JWT with different state-of-the-art elliptic curves. Finally, I gave technical support to the backend team during some sprints. Those tasks were mainly designing, developing and testing microservices using SpringBoot.

# Languages

Spanish	Native
English	C1
German	A2

### **Interests**

- Sports
- German
- Travel
- DIY
- Space
- Cooking

## **Contact**

- A C/ Abedúl, 33, Bj
- 28810, Madrid, Spain
- □ +34 652 957 762
- maximo.garcia.martinez @outlook.com

in linkedin.com/maximo-garcia
-martinez

github.com/onmax

#### Intern Blockchain & Web

Aug. 2020 - Jan. 2021

 $\label{eq:continuous} \mbox{ Department of Blokchain} \mid \mbox{ Cybersecurity unit } \mbox{ Inetum}$ 

Helping to implement the Alastria specification. Developing and testing microservices using SpringBoot. Writing and documenting libraries in Java and TS. Designing and developing websites using various frameworks.

### Fullstack developer

Jan. 2017 - Apr. 2021

DΑ

ETSIINF - UPM

Vue, Angular 2+, Angular JS, Django 2.0 for various project for the Student Union association as project manager working with a group of people for projects like Try IT! congress.

#### Web developer

Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2018

Freelancer

I created few online shops for some clothing brands that were expanding using Shopify. I also worked in DIGA Department (UPM) and Astronomical Observatory of the UPM, making them different websites using Vanilla JS and Angular

## **Education**

#### **Erasmus - Computer Science**

Aug. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Uppsala Üniversitet, Sweden

#### **Computer Engineering**

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2021

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid, Spain

### Senior year - High School

Sep. 2015 - Jan. 2016

Colegio S.Ramón y S.Antonio | Madrid, Spain

#### Sophomore year - High School

Princeton High School | MN, USA

Sep. 2015 - Jan. 2016

## **Publications**

- As an experienced technical contributor to Alastria. 2021. "LACChain ID Framework."
- García Martínez, Máximo J. & García Dópico, Antonio. (2021). "Bike sharing demand forecasting using Recurrent Neural Networks.". Bachelor's Thesis ETSIINF, UPM. Grade with honours.

## **Events**

Winner Huawei Student Developer Hackathon Sweden 2022.

22nd May 2023		
	Máximo José García Martínez	